Greetings. I had a review planned for today, but I kind of fell through. As the game I
was going to review, I can't find. It's just not here. I know I had it. I can't find it.
So I do have something else, though, that I've acquired recently, and it fits right
in with Edutainment Month, so we'll go ahead and take a look at it. And that is not just
regular SimCity. Everybody's pretty much familiar with this SimCity, SimCity Classic. This
right here is SimCity educational version. As you can see, it does not come in a binder.
In fact, this was not sold in stores at all, at least to my knowledge. What this is is
a special edition for teachers and schools, and pretty much anybody that liked SimCity
and the educational and entertaining opportunities that the game or simulation provided. But,
you know, it doesn't really come with much in here. SimCity, you pretty much have SimCity Classic,
yeah, the terrain editor, tiny little booklet here, and, you know, installation stuff, and
reference card. But you have this little manual, and while it's sufficient for learning it,
it's not really that in-depth into, you know, city planning or much of anything. I mean,
it's got this little thing at the back there. That's it. It's got a lot of recommended reading
and, you know, teaching materials and stuff, but obviously it could do it a lot more. And if you
look in the, pretty much any of these software's toys catalogs from Maxis back then, you would see
a tiny little, let's see here, yeah, tiny little educational hat thing, you know, the graduation
tassel, whatever that thing's actually called, I don't know. That's the hat. That little icon means
that there were educational versions of that game available. Again, there's one on SimLife,
and here's one on SimAnt, and of course you'll have one on SimCity, wherever that is in here,
and a SimCity Classic. There we go. So, educational version, totally available, which is
yeah, so that's that. But I had never actually seen one until recently when I ran across this
on eBay and recognized the awkwardness immediately. Yeah, Maxis software toys that teach,
not just regular software toys, they teach. So I expect to be taught here, but first I will have
to remove this taught packaging. So let's go ahead and open this up. This is the first time I've ever
actually seen the contents of one of these things, so it's gonna be pretty cool. Oh yeah, and it's
also worth noting this is the Macintosh version of this. Like any respectable education institution
would have the Macintosh PCs, man, those are for businesses. Education, it's Macintosh, so let's see.
Whoa, okay.
Smells like cellophane. Okay, so very simple here. UPC says lab pack, which is intriguing.
Pretty standard folder.
All right, we have, wow. Oh man, I love how standard these disks look. Yeah,
SimCity Classic, Mac, all rights reserved.
And you pretty much have a license agreement notification right here, which dang, I hate that
they stuck the sticker to the label of the disk. Ooh, that's gotta be a pain to get off.
Well, we'll get to that later. And yes, I do anticipate testing this out.
Here's the teacher's guide, which is pretty cool.
All the nice little preperforated holes here.
This reminds me of the old, uh, like curriculums and stuff I used to have.
Let's see.
This appears to be a Spanish addendum for,
like it looks like this, the regular SimCity functions.
That's interesting. All right, there's the, uh, little slimline manual. Looks like
practically the exact same thing. Just a little bit smaller print as the regular version. And it
also looks like it has the, uh, terrain editor information. Yeah, terrain editor is already
inside the manual for this one. And it's also perforated. Teacher's and perforations, man.
I don't get it. I mean, I do. It's organization. All right, so here's the regular, uh, addendum.
Here we go. Reference card. Hey, teachers, check out our new Maxis educational products,
like SimTunes and SimPark. Wow, this must have been late in the game, like 1996,
97. Yeah, late 96, I would assume.
SimCity 2000 widget workshops in town. SimCity classic. All right, here's, here's the nice one.
Um, this is, uh, information how much this, how much this would have cost. Apparently the lab pack,
which is this one, is $80. All right, so there was a, there were different versions. Lab pack,
which is the one I have here. School edition. Don't know what the difference is. 30 units and 50
units. Uh, sweet. 50 units, $600 for a bunch of SimCity. Oh man. All right, yeah, here we go.
This is the, uh, school site license agreement.
Hmm.
Yeah, basically you have a certain amount of copies of this that you can make and use in your school
legally. Uh, if it was anything like my school back in the day, you just disregarded this entirely
and kind of, uh, copied and did as you please. Let's see, and the Maxis Maxims,
nice full sheet version of this. Uh, this is basically just saying, hey, we're Maxis,
uh, this is contact stuff. There's lots of really snarky remarks and
sarcasm in here. I love these, these things. Um, oh wow. Oh wow. Okay, now this is cool. Field trips
for the mine. The 1996 educational software catalog. I've never seen one of these. Didn't
even know it existed. Okay. Wow. Forget the magic school bus. You got the Maxis school bus right
there. Apparently about to run over a dog. Oh, this is, oh, this is awesome.
All right. So yeah, it's like every educational version here, uh, includes a teacher's guide and,
uh, lessons, which I assume we'll get to here soon when I open that teacher's guide, uh, kit.
And there's, uh, of course, license and duplication rights.
Wow. Holy crap, this is cool. All right, so there you go. You can see the other versions
of these, uh, educational editions of the games. Looks like they're SimLife, SimCity 2000, widget
workshops, SimTown, SimEarth, SimFarm, SimAnt, and SimCity Classic. At least they're shown on, uh,
this little thing here. I remember SimLife actually came with some of this kind of stuff
already. Yeah, in fact, actually it came with this little workbook inside the SimLife package normally.
So that's, that's cool. Social studies. What a drab sounding name, man. If they could call it
anything else, I probably would have enjoyed it more because I actually do like social studies.
I just don't like it when it's called social studies. Wrath of the Gods. I actually have been
looking for this game for years because, uh, I remember that back in the, uh, old Macintosh
systems at the library. SimCity 2000. Basically it's more graphics. I mean, more, uh, information
about the costs and everything. Looks like there's a more detailed table of, uh, SimCity Classic. Looks
like you can get school editions of the graphics sets too, which is a little bizarre. Ah, of course,
SimHealth. Mm-hmm. SimAnt, widget workshop. Widget workshop is friggin awesome. I really should have
reviewed that this month instead of whatever. Xerx Rainforest Lab, as well as Xerx Alaskan
Trek and Learning Safari. Xerx Learning Safari. Didn't that come with Microsoft Bob? Pretty sure
it did. Or at least some versions. And, uh, yeah. Lots of boring stuff in that section. That's, this
is awesome. Wow. Okay, that's, that's entirely cool. That's it. That's everything that's in there. Put all this back.
Mm-hmm. Okay. All right, let's open the, uh, the teacher's guide here. Let me go grab a blade
really quick. Yeah, I really should have done this to begin with, but I'm gonna sort of take a top
down look at things while I'm opening this. That way it'll be a little less glory and such, at least
hopefully. How should I do this? Actually, you know what? Handy little air bubble things, ventilation holes.
Here we have the teacher's guide.
I really should probably put this in the book. That'll make it easier to flip through.
Oh, that's so satisfying. All right, so here we go. An educational companion for SimCity and SimCity Classic.
Teaching with SimCity. Man, I wish I had a SimCity class as a kid. That would have been sweet.
Plated enough as it is.
You know, so basically lots more detailed, uh, educational, uh, learning, teaching kind of
information, uh, integrating with curriculums and stuff like that relating to, uh, SimCity Classic
that you just didn't get with the normal manual.
Yeah, here we go. Yeah, simulations, the objective, what you gotta do, key questions at the end.
Did editing the parks change anything? What did it change? You know, the kind of stuff that
only boring teachers followed all the way through and the cool teachers made this kind of stuff
exciting. So, you know, I mean, uh, off-computer simulations.
So basically it takes like, um, maybe a little bit of history, social studies, looks like even just,
well, it really kind of takes out the math because it does the math for you and just kind of mixes
them all together and, you know, it's SimCity. SimCity. Oh yeah, some of the stuff I was wondering
about. Uh, let's see. Oh, that's cool. Yeah. Oh yeah, these are just bigger versions of the
zone evolution charts that are, uh, in the normal manual as well as the city dynamics chart. Very
helpful. And elements of the city. Yeah, this is what I was wondering about. These are, uh,
copyable pages that you could hand out. It's like worksheets to the students. So yeah,
put their name and their date and all that crap and all that stuff that they put in there and,
you know, see if they can just fill out the different stuff. What are you supposed to do,
draw their city map in here? It's a little involved. Yeah, fill in the blanks.
Invent a way to commute that people might use in the future. Jet powered donkeys.
Yeah, so there you go. I mean, it's about what I expected. It's a typical, uh,
curricula looking kind of thing in regards to SimCity. Lots of copyable worksheets.
I don't think the game itself is any different. Might have a different license screen or about
screen or something. I'm not really sure. So I guess we'll find that out here soon.
So I installed this and hopefully get the stupid sticker off of the sticker
so I can stick it in the Macintosh and try it out.
Okay, so the disc survived somewhat. At least a little bit better than I expected. A little
bit of red stew, but, you know, whatever. So let's pop it into the old LC575 here and see what we get.
Cool. SimCity version 1.4.
C.
All right, so while it's copying over the discs to the hard drive, I just noticed that the
Addendum system information card here is for the IBM PC version, which means this is
absolutely 100% useless to the Macintosh version. In fact, I don't even see installation instructions
for the Macintosh version, so I don't know why this is included. That's pretty funny,
actually. At least they included the correct manual. All right, so let's try it here.
Wouldn't this be a great time to fill out your registration card? Yes, it would.
Access still existed, but alas, they do not.
At least, at the monitors, you have 16 colors or less. All right, force me to.
16 colors, kind of an abomination.
How do you like that?
Cool. Start a new city or load. It looks like the same version as any other version
for the Macintosh. That's version 1.4 C.
What in the awkward music is that?
All right, so it's just playing sound effects.
Let's go to Burns Traffic 1965. Yeah, so it's pretty much SimCity for the Mac.
I don't see anything different here.
About... yeah, so it's version 1.4 C. So, you know, that was pretty typical. I think that was the
last version for the Macintosh. If not, then one of the very last. All right, well, that is
SimCity Classic educational version or teacher's version or the lab kit. If you want to get
technical. For the Macintosh and for other systems, assuming that is because it seems like
pretty much everything else is the same. I love how you get to switch all these color modes.
So, hooray for black and white.
All right, well, it does not like terrain editor, at least on system 761.
So, I guess I won't be showing that. That's okay. All right, well,
thanks for watching, and we'll be one more education, edutainment game coming up.
And, yeah, if you don't know what it is, then let's just say...
Yeah, screw it.